Guide to the New York Times Company records. Arthur Hays Sulzberger papers
New York Public Library
- Series II. Subjects, 1823, 1858, 1875, 1891, 1895, 1900-1910, 1916-1972, 1978-1999, n.d; 210.75 boxes, 9 volumes
  - Anniversaries
    - AHS's Wedding, 1927-1966 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - 50th Anniversary of Ochs's Acquisition of the New York Times, 1946 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - New York Times
      - 80th, 1931 (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - 99th, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - 100th
      - Awards, citations, etc.
      - 1951 (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - 1951 (Box 291, Folder 5)
      - Letters
      - A-E (Box 97, Folder 6-9)
      - F-Q (Box 98, Folder 1-6)
      - R-Z (Box 99, Folder 1-3)
      - Plans, arrangements, etc., 1945-1952 (Box 99, Folder 4-5)
      - 101st, 105th, 110th, 1952, 1956, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - 103rd
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1968 (Box 100, Folder 1-6)
  - Antarctic
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1950, 1953, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1938-1948, 1967-1968 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    Memoranda about anti-Semitic manifestations in U.S. and especially in New York City, and efforts to combat them; diverse publications, leaflets, etc. (1938-1948).Readers' letters protesting alledgedly anti-Semitic terms in news articles and headlines; AHS's and AOS's replies (1967-1968).Memoranda about anti-Semitic manifestations in U.S. and especially in New York City, and efforts to combat them; diverse publications, leaflets, etc. (1938-1948).Readers' letters protesting alledgedly anti-Semitic terms in news articles and headlines; AHS's and AOS's replies (1967-1968).
  - Anti-trust Matters, 1949 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Antihistamines, 1949-1950 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    Includes memoranda about the NYT's policy of rejecting ads for such products.
  - Antiques, 1929-1938, 1950-1965 (Box 101, Folder 5-7)
  - Apparel, Personal, 1942-1967 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Arabian Peninsula
  - Arbitration
  - Architecture and Architects, 1959, 1962-1964 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    Memoranda and letters about establishing the position of architecture critic and the appointment of Ada Louise Huxtable.Memoranda and letters about establishing the position of architecture critic and the appointment of Ada Louise Huxtable.
  - Arctic
  - Argentina, 1929-1959 (Box 102, Folder 1-2)
    Includes correspondence about the difficulty of NYT correspondents in Argentina, restraints on domestic newspapers there, political conditions, especially the Peron regime, detailed, confidential letters of United States Ambassador George Messersmith, the dispute between him and NYT correspondent Frank Kluckhohn, Kluckhohn's mistreatment by the police, and NYT executives' comments on these (1946-1947), and correspondence with Dr. Milton Eisenhower about NYT reports and editorials on the Peron regime and United States policies (1953).
  - Argus Africa News Service, 1960-1962 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Arizona, University of, 1955-1957, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Daily Star, 1949, 1956-1963 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Arkansas Gazette, 1953, 1957-1958 (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Armed Forces Information School
  - Armstrong Memorial Research Foundation, 1956 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Art, 1931-1967 (Box 102, Folder 8-9)
  - Art Critics
  - Art Department, 1934-1960 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Art Directors Club, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Art News and Criticism, 1945-1967 (Box 103, Folder 2-3)
    Includes AHS's memoranda on modern art and Dore Ashton's reviews in the NYT.
  - Articles About AHS, 1930-1961, 1995 (Box 103, Folder 4-7)
  - Articles and Books
    - About ASO, 1935, 1946-1947, 1957-1958, 1961 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - About AHS, 1955 (Box 291, Folder 5)
    - About the NYT, 1924-1968 (Box 104, Folder 1-3)
  - Articles by AHS, 1955 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Arts and Leisure Section
  - Asahi Shimbun, 1933-1967 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Ascension Memorial Church, 1930-1931 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Assiut Hospital
  - Associated Business Publications, Inc.
  - Associated Press
    Includes material on the quality of the Associated Press (AP) service, competition among news services and resulting distortions and exaggerations, editing of dispatches to falsely indicate sources and updating, the free flow of information world-wide, misleading or inaccurate bylines, the accuracy of some AP reports and war dispatches, misleading terms and datelines, editing to falsely indicate updating, disputes between the AP and the NYT about proprietary rights, AP's use of advance copy and proofs of the NYT as tips to its own reporters, the right to dispose of photos after distribution to newspapers, a dispute between the AP and the Newspaper Guild, election news coverage, faking of news, and the NYT's violation of AP release time.
    - Photograph of the board of directors, 1950 (Box 294, Folder 6)
    - General
      - 1958-1968 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - 1941-1957 (Box 105, Folder 1-6)
      - 1927-1940 (Box 106, Folder 1-6)
    - Anti-Trust Suit, 1942, 1945 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence and memoranda about the Chicago Sun's civil antitrust suit to compel the AP to admit all qualified newspapers, ending territorial exclusivity of the AP's membership, and the resulting revision of the AP's bylaws.
    - New York Times Party
      Contains records of the annual cocktail party given at and by the NYT to meet the directors and officers of the AP.
      - 1956-1967 (Box 107, Folder 1-4)
      - 1941-1955 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Wirephoto Service, 1934-1937, 1941, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1958 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Association of College and Research Libraries
  - Associations, 1936-1968 (Box 108, Folder 4-5)
  - Astor, Vincent, Foundation
  - Athenaeum, 1943, 1951-1959 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Atlantic Review, 1955-1956 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic Union Proposal
  - Atlases, 1947 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Atomic Energy Laboratory (Oak Ridge, Tenn.), 1949 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Weapons (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - General, 1946-1956 (Box 109, Folder 2)
      Includes a report of the Secretary of State's committee on international control of atomic energy (1946), James Reston's report on interviews with Lewis L. Strauss, Henry De Wolf Smyth, Vannevar Bush, and Robert Oppenheimer about the Oppenheimer security-clearance case (1954), William L/ Laurence's report on the development of a U-238 bomb, with contrary articles in The Nation and memorandum by Hanson Baldwin, and memoranda between Baldwin and James Reston on atom bombs and the likelihood of conventional, limited war (1956).
    - Hiroshima Bombing, 1955, 1958 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Tests, 1946-1962 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      Includes reports by William Laurence, Robert Plumb, Waldemar Kaempffert, and Dr. Howard Rusk on the effects of fallout (1954), Laurence's confidential report on his off-the-record interview with Isidor Rabi on the proposed moratorium of weapons tests (1956); memoranda by Laurence and others about AHS's plan to attend the Nevada tests (1957), memoranda about proposals to suspend the Nevada tests (1958-1961), and memoranda about the NYT's exclusive reports on a high-altitude test (1959).
  - Audit Bureau of Circulations, 1941 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Aufbau (Reconstruction), 1944, 1954-1955, 1959 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Australia, 1940-1966 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Australian Associated Press
    - General, 1932-1953 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Caricatures, 1940 (Box 291, Folder 5)
  - Australian Newspaper Proprietors Association, 1945 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Australian Newspaper Service, 1940-1959 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Australian Press Association
  - Austria, 1934-1962 (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Automobiles
    - General, 1941-1966 (Box 109, Folder 12)
      Includes mainly letters and memoranda about cars bought by AHS or the NYT for his use, but some material dealing with general automotive news and traffic problems is included.
    - Detroit Luncheons, 1940-1942, 1949 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Aviation
    - General, 1933, 1940-1967 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Accidents
    - Bombing Squadron Flight, 1931 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Byrd, Ricahrd E., 1927-1929 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Costes, Dieudonne and Maurice Bellonte, 1931, 1961 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Earhart, Amelia, 1928 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Kingsford-Smith, Charles, 1930 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Lindbergh, Charles A.
      - General, 1927-1931, 1941, 1953-1954 (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - Banquet booklet, 1927 (Box 291, Folder 5)
    - Nichols, Ruth, 1931 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Partridge, Herbert G., 1927-1929 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - Pilots Training Project, 1940 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Post, Wiley and Harold Gatty, 1931 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Awards to NYT and/or Staff Members
    - General, 1955-1958 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - Ayer Awards, 1933-1962 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Hawks Awards, 1945-1946 (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - Littledale Prize, 1958 (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1949, 1955-1959 (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Page One Awards, 1953, 1961 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - Polk Awards, 1951-1968 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Publisher's Awards
      - General, 1950-1959 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Letters, 1950-1965 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - William the Silent Award, 1950-1956 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Awards, Decorations, Honors and Tributes to AHS
    - Correspondence, 1943, 1953-1961, 1964 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Benjamin Franklin 250th Anniversary certificates, 1956 (Box 291, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Awards
      - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 111, Folder 6)
      - Awards
      - 1938, 1952, 1956-1957 (Box 293, Folder 2)
        Contains awards from China, France, Japan, and Korea.
      - 1937-1956 (Box 294, Folder 2-4)
        Contains awards from Bolivia, China, Finland, France, Greece, Mexico, Poland, and Yugoslavia.
    - Mixed awards
      - 1949-1961 (Box 293, Folder 1)
        Contains awards, etc. from the American Hospital Association, Baron de Hirsch Fund, Carver Seal Committee, Clipper Club, Dallas, Texas, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Employees of the New York Times, Greater New York Hospital Association, Honor Legion of the Police Department of the City of New York, John F. Kennedy, National Union of American and Greek War Veterans, Poor Richard Club, and Publication and Production Departments of the New York Times.
      - 1928-1966 (Box 289, Folder 2-7)
        Contains awards, etc. from the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, American Red Cross, Army of the United States, Arthur Hays Sulzberger Plaza, Associated Press, Columbia University, Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, Graf Zeppelin, Jack Daniels, John H. Finley Award, Metropolitan Conference of the National Federation of Temple Brotherhoods, National Geographic Society, New York Times Pressroom, Thirty Year Club, Time Magazine, and Voice of a Free Press.
    - Roosevelt Medal, 1947-1948 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Awards, Decorations, Honors, and Tributes to ASO
  - Awards to WQXR
  - Ayer, N.W., & Son, 1936-1941 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    Correspondence about Ayer's ads for The Times, its own institutional ads, and company's internal affairs.Correspondence about Ayer's ads for The Times, its own institutional ads, and company's internal affairs.
  - Balloons, 1956 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    Contains a confidential memorandum by Hanson Baldwin on the United States' use of propaganda, weather, and reconnaissance balloons.
  - Bank of New York, 1934, 1957-1959 (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Bankers Trust Co., 1933, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Barber Shops, 1952-1967 (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Barnard College, 1936, 1957-1961 (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Baron de Hirsch Fund, 1935-1941 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc., 1956-1959, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Beacon Press, 1950 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Belgium, 1942-1959 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Bequests of AHS
  - Bequests of ASO
  - Berea College, 1950 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Bergdorf Goodman, 1956-1957 (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Berlin Bureau, 1927-1934, 1939, 1942, 1946-1948 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    Includes letters and memoranda about attempts at censorship and seizure of copies of the NYT by the Nazi regime, plans to close the bureau at the outbreak of World War II, resumption of operations at the end of the war, and plans to move the bureau to West Germany.
  - Berlingske Tidende, 1945-1956 (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Best & Co., 1940-1949, 1956 (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Beth Israel Hospital, 1958, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Better Business Bureau, 1952-1968 (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - Better Times, 1937-1939 (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Bilderberg Conference, 1956-1968 (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Bill of Rights
  - Bill of Rights Commemorative Society, 1942-1950 (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Biography of AHS, 1929-1957, 1968 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Birch, John, Society, 1961 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Birmingham Libel Suits
  - Birmingham News, 1950-1953 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Birth Control
  - Birthdays of AHS
    - General, 1951-1968 (Box 113, Folder 4-10)
    - 50th
    - NYT front page, 1941 (Box 293, Folder 3)
      Contains a special issue of the NYT for AHS's birthday.
    - Scrapbook, 1941
    - 60th, 1951 (Box 282)
    - 75th, 1966 (Box 286)
  - Bishop's University, 1951 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Blackouts, 1961, 1965 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Blacks
  - Blindness
  - Blood Banks, 1942-1961 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Bloomingdale's, 1943, 1953 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - B'nai B'rith, 1936, 1953 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Bodleian Library, 1957 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Bohemian Grove
  - Bolivia, 1956-1963 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Bomb Threats, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Bonn Bureau, 1951-1956 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Bonnie Prince Mining Syndicate, Ltd., 1947 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Book and Educational Division, 1963-1968 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Book Fairs
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1956 (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - Book Review
    Includes material on the policies governing the reviews and reviewers in the Sunday Book Review Section and daily book pages, plans for editorial changes, controversies between reviewers, columnists (especially J. Donald Adams), Lester Markel, and AHS, and controversies with Alfred Knopf and other publishers.
    - 1942-1963 (Box 114, Folder 13-16)
    - 1925-1941 (Box 115, Folder 1-2)
  - Bookplates, 1928, 1932-1934, 1954, 1957 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Books and Literature
    - General, 1934-1965 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, 1875, n.d. (Box 280)
      Contains handwritten copies of prose and poems by famous authors.
  - Books by Staff Members, 1960-1962 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Boston American
  - Boston Conference on Distribution, 1946-1948 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Boston Curb Exchange, 1929 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Boston Herald-Traveler, 1957-1966 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Bowater Paper Co., 1946-1965 (Box 115, Folder 9-10)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1942-1946, 1952-1958 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Box 116 was omitted from this list. (Box 116)
  - Boycotts
  - Brandeis University, 1956, 1962-1963 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Braniff International Airways, 1959-1960 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Brazil, 1928-1938, 1954-1965 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Bretton Woods Conference, 1944-1945 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Bridge column, 1946-1960 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Brisbane Courier-Mail
  - Bristol-Myers Co., 1961 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - British Information Services, 1946-1959 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Broadcast Desk
  - Brooklyn Eagle, 1933, 1955 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1959 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn-Queens-Long Island Section, 1932, 1935 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Brooks Brothers
  - Brooks School, 1949-1951 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Brown University, 1944, 1955, 1959-1961 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Brussels Bureau, 1958 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Buenos Aires Bureau
  - Buildings
    - General, 1924, 1931-1937, 1952, 1959-1961 (Box 117, Folder 14)
      Includes memoranda on diverse properties owned by the NYT including F. A. Cox's reports on valuation of all properties (1959) and tax assessments (1959-1961).
    - Commercial
      - 10th-11th Avenues, 44th-45th Streets
      - General, 1931-1955 (Box 118, Folder 1-2)
        Includes correspondence about repairs required, plans for a printing plant to be built above the railroad cut, possible sale of property, and renting of stores (1932-1938), possible uses of the property, a proposal for acquisition of a New York City school and a small factory, located in the same block (1951-1954).
      - Architectural drawings and plans, 1931, 1954 (Box 293, Folder 5)
        Includes engineers' drawing of a possible NYT plant (1954) and a title company's survey (1931).
      - 43rd Street
      - General, 1928-1938, 1943-1962 (Box 118, Folder 3-6)
        Includes letters, memoranda, and other documents about an appraisal of the Astor leasehold (easterly part of plot) (1930), use of subsurface strip, rental of stores at the western end (1936), purchase of the 44th Street Theatre, plans for major renovation of building and expansion to the 44th Street side, including new elevators, newsprint storage space, and space for WQXR, zoning regulations; financing of project (1943-1944), construction problems, progress, and delays (1945-1948), construction of WQXR studios (1947-1950), memoranda on the possible sale of the building in light of the proposed move to the West Side Plant (1955-1960), and memoranda on further alterations undertaken or proposed (1960-1962).
      - Interior Decoration, 1946-1968 (Box 119, Folder 1)
      - 44th Street
      - 48th Street Warehouse, 1923-1934 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - 101 West End Avenue
      - 113 Nassau Street
      - 165 Broadway, 1933 (Box 119, Folder 3)
      - Brooklyn Plant, 1935, 1945-1952 (Box 119, Folder 4)
      - Park Row
      - Times Tower
      - General, 1924-1966 (Box 119, Folder 5-8)
        Includes letters, memoranda, and other documents about building repairs, maintenance and alterations, space rentals, effects of subway operations, electric news sign and New Year's Eve display, Francis E. J. Wilde's patents for the electric news sign, contract for its installation, Wilde's letter explaining the cost overrun and offering to forfeit royalties, and AHS's letter explaining how the news bulletins are selected and edited (1927-1936), reports on the condition of the building and steps to repair and modernize it, the sale to Douglas Leigh, Inc., the resale to and modernization by Allied Chemical Corp., (1956-1966), and the building's designation as a landmark (1957).
      - Plans, 1927, 1938 (Box 293, Folder 5)
        Contains plans for a section of the electric news sign (1927) and exterior repairs (1938).
      - West Side Plant
      - General, 1954-1964 (Box 120, Folder 1-5)
        Includes material regarding the acquisition of the 101 West End Avenue property from the New York Central Railroad Co., construction problems and progress, maintenance and traffic problems, and temporary space rental to other companies.
      - Architectural drawings, 1955-1957 (Box 293, Folder 6)
        Contains architectural drawings of the proposed Plant.
    - Residential
      - 5 East 80th Street
      - General, 1924-1950 (Box 121, Folder 1)
        Includes a cable regarding ASO's gift of the building to IOS (1924), correspondence about legal matters, repairs, maintenance, insurance, efforts to sell the building, and its ultimate sale to Lewis S. Rosenstiel (1950).
      - Appraiser's reports, 1926, 1930 (Box 281)
      - 308, 310, and 314 West 75th Street
      - General, 1936, 1940-1955 (Box 121, Folder 2)
        Includes letters, memoranda, legal documents, bills and receipts, and other papers dealing with the management of these properties by the Ochs Estate and its efforts to dispose of them.
      - Blueprints, 1940 (Box 293, Folder 6)
        Contains blueprints for proposed alterations to 308 West 75th St.
      - 1115 Fifth Avenue
      - General, 1950-1968 (Box 121, Folder 3-4)
        Includes correspondence about purchase of the apartment, floor plans, with proposed alterations, memoranda, notes, etc. about maintenance and furnishings of the apartment, and appraisal of furnishings as of April 1958.
      - Blueprint and architectural drawings, 1950 (Box 293, Folder 7)
        Contains a blueprint and architectural drawings of the apartment.
      - Abenia, 1923-1925, 1937-1939, 1945, 1952, 1956, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 5)
        Includes correspondence about repairs, maintenance, and staff, papers about the acquisition of an adjacent property from the Peabodys (1925), and documents about the sale of Abenia (1939, 1956, 1960).
      - Hillandale (Stamford, CT.)
      - General
        Includes correspondence, memoranda, notes, legal documents, and other records about the estate. They concern mainly the initial purchase and the acquisition of adjacent properties, maintenance of the house, other buildings, the grounds, and relations with neighbors. The property was acquired in part by the Ochs Estate and in part by AHS personally, and many of the documents concern the legal ramification of this, and include correspondence with the children and attorneys about the acquisitions and future disposition of the property. Included are correspondence on the disposition of the property after his death (1960, 1965), lists of property acquired, with acreage and cost (1960-1961, 1965), a list of property improvements since 1949, correspondence with the architect, builder, landscape architect, and other contractors, specifications, bids, contracts, and a brochure about the initial property (1949).
      - 1964-1968 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - 1959-1963 (Box 122, Folder 1-6)
      - 1949-1958 (Box 123, Folder 1-5)
      - Photograph album, 1949-1955 (Box 289, Folder 1)
      - Photographs, 1946, 1949, 1954, 1961 (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - Hillandale (White Plains, N. Y.)
      - General, 1930-1958 (Box 124, Folder 1)
        Includes correspondence about ASO's purchase of the estate, repairs and maintenance, the sale of the property by the Ochs Estate, and its subsequent disposition.
      - Blueprints, architectural drawings, and photograph, 1935-1936, 1938-1940 (Box 293, Folder 7)
        Contains blueprints and architectural drawings of the estate.
      - Photographs, 1945-1948 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Bulgaria, 1936-1937 (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1952 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Business Manager
  - Busts of Adolph S. Ochs
  - Byrd Associates, 1937-1938 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Cabot Prizes, 1947-1966 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Cafeteria (New York Times)
  - Cambodia, 1952, 1956 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Camp Adolph Ochs, 1935-1939 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Canada, 1940-1964 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Canadian Press
  - Cancer
  - Caneel Bay Plantation, 1957-1959 (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - CARE, 1947-1948, 1961-1962 (Box 124, Folder 11)
  - Carlsbad Cavern
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1951 (Box 124, Folder 12)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1940 (Box 124, Folder 13)
  - Cartoons and Caricatures, 1936-1964 (Box 124, Folder 14)
    Includes memmoranda and correspondence about the selection of cartoons, the NYT's reasons for not publishing its own cartoons, and the practice of reprinting cartoons from other newspapers without payment.
  - Castle Clinton National Monument
  - Catherwood Foundation
  - Catholic Church
  - The Catholic Leader, 1957 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Catholics
  - Catskill Daily Mail, 1954 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Cemeteries
  - Censorship, 1939-1961 (Box 125, Folder 3-5)
  - Central Conference of American Rabbis
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1954 (Box 125, Folder 6)